(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-31T21:59:05.974583",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
周防パトラ 誕生日3Dライブ 2025
Suou Patra Birthday 3D Live 2025
燃え上がれ 燃え上がれ 燃え上がれ ガンダム
Fire up! Fire up! Fire up, Gundam!
君よ 走れ
You, run!
まだ怒りに燃える闘志があるなら
If you still have a raging, burning fighting spirit,
巨大な敵を 討てよ 討てよ 討てよ
strike down the giant enemy! Strike down! Strike down!
正義の怒りをぶつけろ ガンダム
Strike with the rage of justice, Gundam!
機動戦士 ガンダム ガンダム
Mobile Warrior Gundam! Gundam!
立ち上がれ 立ち上がれ 立ち上がれ ガンダム
Stand up! Stand up! Stand up, Gundam!
君よ 叫べ
You, shout!
まだ絶望に沈む悲しみあるなら
If you still have sadness sinking into despair,
恐怖をはらって 行けよ 行けよ 行けよ
dispel the fear and go! Go! Go!
うず巻く血潮を燃やせ ガンダム
Burn the swirling tide of blood, Gundam!
機動戦士 ガンダム ガンダム
Mobile Warrior Gundam! Gundam!
皆さん！
Everyone!
周防パトラ生誕祭お越しいただいてどうもありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to Suou Patra's Birthday Live!
パトラ、行きます！
Patra, launching!
よみがえる よみがえる よみがえる ガンダム
Reviving! Reviving! Reviving, Gundam!
君よ 掴め
You, seize it!
まだ愛にふるえる心があるなら
If you still have a heart that trembles with love,
平和を求めて 翔べよ 翔べよ 翔べよ
seeking peace, fly! Fly! Fly!
銀河へ向かって 翔べよ ガンダム
Fly towards the galaxy, Gundam!
機動戦士 ガンダム ガンダム
Mobile Warrior Gundam! Gundam!
魂が振るい立つような この力
This power that makes my soul tremble...
次々とよみがえる 歴戦の記憶
Memories of past battles awakening one after another...
これは 先代たちの...
These are... from my predecessors...
今... 受け継ごう
Now... I shall inherit it.
歴代のパトラの 力と記憶を！
The power and memories of all past Patras!
はい、ということで！
Alright, so!
最終形態周防パトラでーす！
I'm the final form, Suou Patra!
今回も豪華ステージ、そして新衣装！
Once again, a gorgeous stage, and a new outfit!
さらに！巨大カニカマもいるよ〜！ということで
Plus! There's even a giant crab stick! So...
改めまして、こんばんはー！
Once again, good evening!
周防パトラ生誕祭にお越しいただき、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to Suou Patra's Birthday Festival!
はい！見てください、まずは新衣装！
Yes! Take a look, first is my new outfit!
気になってる方も多いと思うんですけど...
I think a lot of you were curious about it...
あ、椅子のほうが気になりますか？これロマサガ2風です、はい！
Oh, are you more curious about the chair? It's styled after Romancing SaGa 2, yes!
はい！じゃあ下からね！
Alright, let's start from the bottom!
なんと！はい、靴！
Look at this! Yes, the shoes!
ちゃんと今回も...あ、違う、ヒールがあります！間違えた、ヒールがあります！
This time too... wait, no, it has heels! I made a mistake, it has heels!
そして、このベルトも可愛いでしょ？はい！
And this belt is cute too, right? Yes!
で、今回は鉄壁のスカートになっております！
And this time, it's an ironclad skirt!
結構ね、動いても、はい！
Even if I move around a lot, see!
鉄壁で頑丈になっております！
It's ironclad and sturdy!
それから、おへそー！
And then, the belly button~!
見てみてみてー！セクシーでしょ？
Look, look, look~! Isn't it sexy?
そして、ベルトもね、がっちりになっております！
And the belts are also securely fastened!
白衣装の時よりちょっと抑えられてるんでね、揺れがちょっと足りないかもしれないんですけど、今回もボインボインでお送りいたします！
It's held down a bit more than with the white outfit, so the jiggle might be a little less, but I'll still bring you boing-boings this time too!
そしてそして、じゃーん！ポニーテール！新髪型になっております！
And next up, ta-da! A ponytail! It's a brand-new hairstyle!
ハートのね、アクセサリーが揺れて可愛いでしょ、これも！
The heart accessory sways, isn't it cute too?
ほらほらほら！
Look, look, look!
という感じでね、とっても可愛い新衣装になりましたー！
So as you can see, it became a super cute new outfit!
さらに、みんなが気になってると思うんですけど...
Furthermore, I think everyone is curious about this...
はい！じゃーん！なんと、脱げまーす！
Yes! Ta-da! Believe it or not, it comes off~!
え、これYouTube的に大丈夫かな？ま、大丈夫かな？
Wait, is this okay for YouTube? Well, it should be okay, right?
え、見てみてみてみて！
Hey, look look look look!
こうね、ハートのくり抜きがあるんですよ！背中の筋がまたセクシーですねー！
See, there's a heart cutout! The line on my back is so sexy too~!
あ、そうそうそう！今回もね、ちゃんと、はい！脇が丸見えになっております！
Oh, right, right, right! This time too, yes! My armpits are fully visible!
たくさんたくさん、スクショ待ってまーす！
I'm waiting for lots and lots of screenshots~!
はい、ということで、ハッシュタグ「#周防パトラ生誕祭」でよろしくお願いします！
Alright, so please post with the hashtag #周防パトラ生誕祭!
感想とかね、あの、コメント待ってるよ！
I'm waiting for your thoughts and comments!
お、可愛いコメントいっぱいありがとうー！
Oh, thank you for all the cute comments~!
はーい！いっぱいね、撮ってくださいね！
Yes! Take lots of photos, okay?
ふんふんふん...なんかセクシーな格好、どうやればいいのか分からないんだけど...
Hmm, hmm... I'm not really sure how to do sexy poses though...
皆さんのスクショテクにお任せしまーす！
I'll leave it to everyone's screenshot skills!
じゃ、早速次の曲いきたいと思いまーす！
Now then, let's move on to the next song!
A-happy 悩める人の向上
A-happy, complaining troubled souls
てんで言っているんだ 死んでいるんだ
keep insisting that they are dead.
命を逸らした過去も 退屈な未来も
A past that strayed from life, a boring future,
カウンセリング屋に嫌気が差して
sick and tired of the counselors.
A-happy, A-lucky, Be happy, A-get-on
ねえねえねえねえ なんだかどうして 戦っていたいようなそんな気がするの
Hey hey hey hey, why do I feel like I want to keep fighting somehow?
ぶれられない ぶれだくもない 過去の自分自分自分自分と
Unwavering, not wanting to stray, with my past self, self, self, self,
まったくに死んでる 透明な亡霊と
with a transparent ghost that is completely dead,
体験したい 体験したい 記憶の奥
wanting to experience, wanting to experience deep in memories.
残念 もういないのに
Too bad, even though it's already gone.
あっちがいい こっちがいい 愛路に愛路に
"That way is better, this way is better", in love's path, in love's path,
惑わされているのは 今の自分
the one being led astray is my current self.
ナンセンス 言えないでいる
Nonsense, unable to speak,
言え コンプレックス
speak up, complex,
取り憑かれているみたい
like being possessed,
巻きついたまま まだ
still wrapped around, still
解けない ありし日の自分
untanglable past self.
A-get-on
慎重の無い オンマイトマインドのデータ
Careless data on my mind,
生きていることとは 変わり続けること
living means continuing to change.
不幸に甘んじて 満足するなよ
Don't just settle for misfortune and be satisfied!
幸せになろうとしないなんて卑怯だ
Not trying to be happy is cowardly.
この世この世は 奇想奇想ファンタジー
This world, this world is a bizarre fantasy.
次は鬼が出るか 蛇が出るか
Will a demon appear next, or a snake?
であってであって やっと始まる物語
Encounters after encounters, the story finally begins.
さあ 人か化け物か
Now, human or monster?
かわす打擲
Dodging the strikes!
Ah future, can change the past
Past, ah future, laugh on the future, right?
なんだかどうして 未来になんぞ何にも
Somehow, why expect nothing from the future?
望めないような気がして
Feeling like there's nothing to hope for,
もう十分生きている 既視感とテンプレ食傷
having lived enough, sick of cliché déjà vu,
劇的な劇毎の 気配もない
without a hint of any dramatic play.
残念
Too bad.
済んだ経験の 因果が描かれた
The causality of past experiences was drawn,
神話は退屈な進化
myth is a boring evolution,
容赦、刺激が欲しいんだ
want relentless excitement,
ちょっと成り立った
barely established.
ランディ 整っていくガイダンス
Randy, neatly arranged guidance,
増えるコンプライアンス 伏せさせられていくみたい
increasing compliance, feeling like being forced to obey.
あじさい...
Hydrangea...
アゲて シンジラナイ
Pump it up, unbelievable!
Oh my god の連鎖
An endless chain of "Oh my god"s!
いつの世も 過去も未来も 今にあるんだ
In any era, the past and future exist right now!
生きていることを 屈辱に挟み
Holding onto life through adversity,
目指せ ハッピーエンド
aim for a happy ending!
アゲて シンジラナイ
Pump it up, unbelievable!
Oh my に生きてるんだ
Living life full of "Oh my!"
幸せを諦めてしまわない人であれ
Be someone who never gives up on happiness!
ただ苦しみに耐えて耐えているだけじゃ
If you just keep enduring suffering,
死んでるのと同じ
it's no different from being dead.
屍のアゲト
Just a walking corpse!
悩める人よ
O troubled people,
立ち上がれ 今こそ
stand up right now!
目指せよ 生きているんだろ
Aim high, you're alive, aren't you?
不幸に浸るも 幸せになるのも
Wallowing in misery or being happy,
そう 全部全部 お前次第
yes, it's all up to you!
ここに到達したい
I want to reach right here,
愛が愛し合う場所
a place where love loves love!
ピース ピース
Peace, peace!
しっかりしっかり！
Listen up, listen up!
誕生日グッズのお知らせだよ！
Here's an announcement for birthday goods!
なんと パトラのでっかい...
Guess what? Patora's huge...
マウスパッドや バスタオル
mousepad and bath towel,
そして とっても可愛いアクリルスタンド
plus a super cute acrylic stand,
A4サイズのファイル
A4 size clear file,
色んなグッズがある誕生日グッズが登場だよ！
a line-up of various birthday goods is available!
受注生産なので 売り切れの心配なし！
They're made-to-order, so no risk of selling out!
8月32日までの受付です！
Pre-orders are open until August 32nd!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you so much!
FINAL FANTASY V ビッグブリッヂの死闘
[FINAL FANTASY V - Battle at the Big Bridge]
UNDERTALE Megalovania
[UNDERTALE - Megalovania]
ロマンシング サ・ガ2 七英雄バトル
[Romancing SaGa 2 - Seven Heroes Battle]
放たれた矢が標的に向かうように
Like an arrow shot toward its target,
自らの気持ちも向かって行く
my own feelings head straight forward.
理由などなく そこに宿命あるだけ
With no reason needed, destiny is simply there.
ただ進む 仲間と共に行く
I just forge ahead, moving forward with my comrades.
気持ちは一つ
Our feelings are as one.
水面に映る君は遠く
Reflected on the water's surface, you are far away...
開いたゲートを見つめてる
Staring at the opened gate,
果てしなく続く
extending without end.
歪んだワールド 傷つける強さ
A distorted world, the strength to wound.
未知なる限界を打ち破れ
Break through unknown limits!
君は Summon Ride!
You are Summon Ride!
時は満ちて Summon Ride!
The time has come, Summon Ride!
意思を宿し 願いを抱き集め
Harboring resolve, gathering our desires,
すべてを超えて突き抜けるの
we'll break through beyond everything!
Summon Ride! 荒野を駆け
Summon Ride! Running through the wasteland,
Summon Ride! ここに今
Summon Ride! Right here, right now,
約束の地へ 駆け抜けるの
running through to the promised land!
君は Summon Ride!
You are Summon Ride!
時を超えて Summon Ride!
Beyond time, Summon Ride!
祈り届け 炎を絆に変えて
Sending our prayers, turning flames into bonds,
一点突破突き抜けるの
breaking through a single point!
Summon Ride! 次元を超え
Summon Ride! Beyond dimensions,
Summon Ride! すべてはいま
Summon Ride! Everything is now,
約束の地へ 駆け抜けるの
running through to the promised land!
はい！ということで、聴いてくれてありがとうございました！
Alright! Thank you so much for listening!
今 何をやっているかというと
As for what I'm doing right now...
とってもこの後 可愛いゲストが来るので フェロモンを出しまくっていました！
Very cute guests are coming after this, so I was pumping out my pheromones!
はぁー、なんかドキドキするなー
Phew, I'm feeling nervous...
それでは、呼びたいと思います！
Well then, I'd like to call them out!
本日のスペシャルゲスト、おいでー！
Today's special guests, come on out!
おはよー！ばうばう！
Good morning! Bau bau!
ハッピーバースデー！ - ありがとうー！
Happy Birthday! - Thank you!
いやぁ、FUWAMOCOちゃんの2人に来てもらいましたー！
Yay, we have FUWAMOCO joining us today!
じゃあ自己紹介をお願いします！ - はい！
Please introduce yourselves! - Sure!
チワワじゃないよ！フワワだよー！
I'm not a Chihuahua! I'm Fuwawa!
フワワじゃないよ！モココだよー！
I'm not Fuwawa! I'm Mococo!
hololive English -Advent- の魔界の番犬シスターズ
From hololive English -Advent-, the Demon World Guard Dog Sisters...
ふたり合わせて、FUWAMOCOです！ばうばう！
Together, we are FUWAMOCO! Bau bau!
かわいい！パトラ様！ - ありがとうございます！
Cute! Patra-sama! - Thank you so much!
いやー、FUWAMOCOちゃんは パトラがね、ASMRの音声をプロデュースして
Well, Patra actually produced an ASMR voice pack for FUWAMOCO...
ね、その時 濃厚な時間を過ごさせていただいたんだよね
Right, we spent such an intense and lovely time together then.
そう、楽しかった！ - 楽しかった！
Yes, it was so much fun! - It was fun!
2人のね、ASMRボイス販売中なので、よろしくお願いします！
Their ASMR voice packs are currently on sale, so please check them out!
よろしくお願いします！ - なんだか恥ずかしい…
Please check them out! - It's kinda embarrassing...
でも今日はパトラの誕生日だから、なんか2人からご褒美がもらえるって聞いたんだけど…
But since today is Patra's birthday, I heard I might get a reward from you two...
ご褒美？ パトラ様のご褒美？
A reward? A reward for Patra-sama?
ご褒美聞いてないですよ！
We didn't hear about any reward!
え〜？ 聞いちゃった！ - ほら〜
Eh? But I heard about it! - See~
せっかくの誕生日だしね！
Since it's my birthday after all!
ご褒美…どうしようっか？
What should the reward be?
ハグとか…
Maybe a hug...
ハグ！ハグちゃん！ - ハグお願いしてもいい？
A hug! Huggie! - Can I ask for a hug?
はい！もうどこでも触ってください！ありがとうございます！
Yes! Feel free to touch me anywhere! Thank you so much!
ツノハグです！じゃあ
It's a horn hug! Alright then...
せーの！ - ハッピーバースデー！
One, two... - Happy Birthday!
幸せ〜！
So happy~!
フワワの方がなんかむにむにしてる… - あ、むにむに？
Fuwawa feels kind of squishy... - Ah, squishy?
おっとっとっと！
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
いやー、モコちゃんも可愛いんだけどね！
Well, Moco-chan is super cute too!
モコちゃんはね、モコちゃん妹なんだから！
Moco-chan is the little sister, after all!
かわいい！かわいい！
Cute! So cute!
可愛い！がんばってる！可愛い！可愛い！ご褒美だ〜！
Cute! She's trying so hard! So cute! What a treat~!
今日はね、3人でまたね、歌が…
Today, the three of us get to sing...
歌えると！ - イエーイ！
Sing together again! - Yay!
あ、じゃあちょっとパト、露出が激しいので着ますね！ほい！
Ah, Pato is showing a bit too much skin, so let me put something on! There!
かわいい〜！ - ありがとうー！
Cute~! - Thank you!
じゃあ、早速いきますか！ - はい！
Shall we get right to it then? - Yes!
それでは聴いてください！「さくらんぼキッズ」！
Please listen to "Sakuranbo Kids"!
さくらんぼキッズ
[Song: Sakuranbo Kids]
呆れ顔 珍しいこのドキドキは
An exasperated face, this unusual excitement
君の腕の中で溢れ出す
overflows within your arms.
ポロリこぼれた涙 さくらんぼ
Tears spilling out like cherries,
もう一回ぎゅっと抱きしめて
hug me tight one more time!
好き 好き 好き 好き 好き 好き 好き
Love you, love you, love you, love you...
はいはい！ 好き 好き 好き 好き
Yes, yes! Love you, love you, love you...
まだまだかな？ 君のハート ちょっと酸っぱい？ - 本当？
Not yet? Is your heart a little sour? - Really?
おやおやおや？ 待ちきれない このままじゃ
Oh dear? I can't wait like this any longer...
決まして顔で決め手！
Make up your mind with a strike of a pose!
遠くに行くのは嫌だよ
I don't want to go far away.
何気なく ふわっと
Casual and gentle,
手首まわして
twirling my wrist,
瞳近づく
our eyes draw closer.
本当はね ずっと好きだったの
Truth is, I've loved you all along.
内緒だよ イェイ！
It's a secret, yeah!
あーらら 小さな胸が震えてる
Oh dear, my small heart is trembling.
抱きしめられたら 壊れちゃうよ
If you hug me, I might just break.
夢で見ていたのより 切ないね
It's more heartbreaking than in my dreams.
だからもっと ぎゅっとしてね
So hold me tighter.
ほろり 涙があふれちゃう
Tears slip and spill over.
大人になるための 痛みくらい
It's just the growing pain of becoming an adult.
君に触れられた場所から 溶けてゆく
Melting away from the places you touched.
Kissはちょっと 遠くまでね
Save the kiss for a bit further.
好き 好き 好き 好き 好き 好き
Love, love, love, love, love, love!
ハイ！ハイ！ 好き 好き 好き 好き
Yay! Yay! Love, love, love, love!
好き 好き 好き 好き 好き 好き きゅんきゅん！
Love, love, love, love, love, love, swoon!
やだ やだ やだよ
No, no, I don't want to!
よそ見は嫌だよ
Don't look away from me.
もう ぎゅーって抱いて
Hold me tight already.
はな はな はな 私もまだ 今夜もまだ
Don't let go, I'm not done yet, not tonight!
君の余裕が グサッと
Your composure pierces right...
胸の奥に 刺さるよ
...into the depths of my heart.
この私 スパッと
Make me cleanly...
忘れさせてね
...forget it all.
優しい吐息で
With your soft breath,
ギュッとしちゃう 内緒だよ イェイ！
I'll hug you tight. It's a secret, yeah!
あーらら 唇が触れすぎる
Oh dear, our lips are touching too much.
君のまつげが 瞳に映る
Your eyelashes reflect in my eyes.
鼓動の波打ち 急上昇
The surge of my heartbeat spikes.
だけどちょっと ちょっとかなり幸せ
But I'm actually pretty, pretty happy.
小鳥みたいに 止まる瞬間に
Like a little bird, the moment it perches,
壊れそうな心 溶けるの
my fragile heart melts away.
赤く熟した 私 さくらんぼ
Ripe and red, I am a cherry.
君とずっと つながっていたい
I want to be connected with you forever.
あぁ 神様
Ah, God...
この唇は 彼と会うために 生まれてきたのですね
these lips were born just to meet him, weren't they?
あー すまし顔で決めて
Ah, putting on a cool face,
気取ったフリは イヤだよ
I hate pretending to be refined.
何気なく ふわっと
Casual and gentle,
首を回して 瞳近づく
turning my head, our eyes draw close.
だってね こんなの初めてなの
Because, you know, this is my first time.
内緒だよ イェイ！
It's a secret, yeah!
あーらら 大切なこのドキドキは
Oh dear, this precious fluttering feeling
君の腕の中で あふれだす
spills over within your arms.
ほろり こぼれた涙 さくらんぼ
Tears that fell like cherries.
もっとギュッと ずっと抱いてて
Hold me tighter, keep holding me forever.
あーらら 世界がくるり回る
Oh dear, the world is spinning around.
ふわふわ 夢心地 風にまかせ
A fluffy dreamlike feeling, leaving it to the wind.
ずっと待ってた 恋は止まらない
The love I've been waiting for won't stop.
だからずっと 離さないで
So don't ever let me go.
好き 好き 好き 好き 好き 好き
Love, love, love, love, love, love!
ハイ！ハイ！ 好き 好き 好き 好き
Yay! Yay! Love, love, love, love!
好き 好き 好き 好き 好き 好き きゅんきゅん！
Love, love, love, love, love, love, swoon!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
みんなー！
Everyone!
周防パトラ生誕祭 盛り上げてくれてどうもありがとう！
Thank you so much for hyping up Suou Patra's Birthday Festival!
まだまだ歌っていくから 盛り上げ よろしくお願いします！
I'm still gonna sing more, so please get excited with me!
偉大なる悪魔は 実は大天使パトラちゃん様なのだ！
[Song Title: The Great Demon is Actually Archangel Patra-chan-sama!]
いくよー！
Here we go!
生きてる世界で一番
The number one in the living world,
頭なでて 甘やかしたの
pat my head and pamper me.
転んで擦り傷を泣かないで
Don't cry over scrapes when you fall,
戦うのさ モンスターに負けないで
fight on and don't lose to the monsters.
自分の運命は
Carve out your own destiny...
自分で切り開け
...by yourself!
バカって言うほうがバカ
The one calling others stupid is the stupid one!
超セクシーでキュートで天才ボディが
My super sexy, cute, and genius body...
国宝級な最高級の ボン・ボン・イイボディ
...is national treasure tier, top grade, bon-bon great body!
むにむにむにむに はーってむにゅ
Muni-muni-muni-muni, haa~ munyu!
そもそもこんなに可愛いのに
Even though I'm so cute in the first place,
いつから悪魔と誤解されていた？
since when was I misunderstood as a demon?
そうだよ そうだよ 誤解だよ 私は天使のような女の子！
That's right, it's a misunderstanding! I'm an angel-like girl!
右に迷ったんじゃない
It's not that I got lost going right,
地球が逆回転したんじゃない？
didn't the Earth just spin in reverse?
人生いつでもぶっつけ本番 いつでも自分が主人公！
Life is always unscripted, you are always the main character!
あー 何だか疲れたな 時代が追いつくまで待とう
Ah, I'm kinda tired. Let's wait until the era catches up.
今日も誕生日！
Today is my birthday too!
ちょっと ちょっと 何てよそ見しているのよ
Hey, hey, why are you looking away?
こんなに 大好きなのに...
Even though I love you so much...
1cm 2cm 3cm 4cm ヒール込みで
1cm, 2cm, 3cm, 4cm, including heels,
154cm
I'm 154 cm!
いいの なんだっていい
It's fine, whatever's fine!
今こそ一致団結
Now is the time to unite!
パトラちゃん様に愛を込めろ
Pour your love into Patra-chan-sama!
愛を込めろ！
Pour your love!
生きてるだけで偉い魔
You're amazing just for being alive-ma!
人生短かいなら 好きなことやって
If life is short, do what you love
生きていきたい
and live life to the fullest!
楽しい方でいいでしょ
It's better to choose the fun way, right?
生きてるだけで偉い魔
You're amazing just for being alive-ma!
たまには甘えて甘やかして魔
Sometimes pamper yourself and be pampered-ma!
転んで自信をなくさないで
Don't lose confidence just because you fell down!
戦うモンスターに負けないで
Don't lose to the monsters you fight!
自分の運命は自分で切り開け
Carve out your own destiny yourself!
我が自由が我が
My freedom is my own!
セクシーでキュートで天才プリティな
Sexy, cute, genius, pretty,
魔界のハイテク魔王のボインボインビッグスマイル
Demon Realm high-tech Demon Lord's boin-boin big smile!
むにむにむにむに ハッピーむにゅ
Muni muni muni muni, happy munyu!
みんなー！
Everyone!
コメントでーい！どうもありがとー！
Thanks so much for all the comments!
見えているよー！
I can see you!
おっ パトラちゃん可愛いって打ってるー？
Oh, are you typing "Patra-chan is cute"?
ちょっとそこの君 サボってるんじゃないよー！
Hey, you over there, don't slack off!
画面の向こう見えてるぞー！
I can see past the screen!
さあさあさあさあ コメント打ってー！
Come on, keep typing those comments!
笑われても気にしないで
Don't mind if you get laughed at!
そのまま終わるより素晴らしい誇り
Having pride is far better than giving up!
再会の約束を忘れるな
Don't forget our promise to meet again!
格好良く生きろ
Live your life coolly!
傷ついた思い出に負けない自分になれ
Become someone who won't lose to painful memories!
みんなー！
Everyone!
盛り上げてくれてどうもありがとー！
Thanks so much for hyping this up!
この後は一緒に パトラちゃん様と言ってください！
Next, please say "Patra-chan-sama" together with me!
せーの！
Ready, go!
パトラちゃん様ー！
Patra-chan-sama!
どうもありがとー！
Thank you so much!
ちょっぴり
A little bit...
生きてるだけで偉い魔
You're amazing just for being alive-ma!
人生短かいなら 好きなことやって
If life is short, do what you love
生きていきたい
and live life to the fullest!
楽しい方でいいでしょ
It's better to choose the fun way, right?
生きてるだけで偉い魔
You're amazing just for being alive-ma!
たまには甘えて甘やかして魔
Sometimes pamper yourself and be pampered-ma!
転んで自信をなくさないで
Don't lose confidence just because you fell down!
戦うモンスターに負けないで
Don't lose to the monsters you fight!
自分の運命は自分で切り開け
Carve out your own destiny yourself!
我が自由が我が
My freedom is my own!
セクシーでキュートで天才プリティな
Sexy, cute, genius, pretty,
魔界のハイテク魔王のボインボインビッグスマイル
Demon Realm high-tech Demon Lord's boin-boin big smile!
むにむにむにむに ハッピーむにゅ
Muni muni muni muni, happy munyu!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
もう一回！
One more time!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! Yeah!
移動してるよ！ちょっと待ってね！
[Title: Moving to the next stage! Please wait a moment!]
Quiet Night C.E.73
[Title: Quiet Night C.E.73]
ハイ！みなさーん！
Hi, everyone!
ラクス・クラインでーす！
I'm Lacus Clyne!
まだまだ生誕祭盛り上げていってくださいねー！
Please keep hyping up the birthday festival!
静かなこの夜に
On this quiet night,
あなたを待っているの
I am waiting for you.
あのとき忘れた
Come pick up the smile
微笑みを取りに来て
you forgot back then.
あれから少しだけ
Since then, a little bit
時間が過ぎて
of time has passed,
思い出が優しくなったね
and memories have become gentle.
星の降る場所で
Where stars fall,
あなたが笑っていることをいつも願ってた
I always prayed that you were smiling.
今遠くても
Even if we're far apart now,
また会えるよね
we'll surely meet again.
いつから微笑みは
Since when did smiles
こんなに儚くて
become so fleeting?
一つの間違いで
Because just one mistake
壊れてしまうから
can break them completely.
大切なものだけを光に変えて
Turning only the precious things into light,
遠い空超えて行く強さで
with the strength to cross distant skies...
星の降る場所へ
To the place where the stars fall
想いをあなたに届けたい
I want to deliver my feelings to you
いつも側にいる
I'm always by your side
冷たさを抱きしめるから
I will embrace that coldness
今遠くても きっと会えるね
Even if we're far apart now, we'll surely meet again
歌うから生誕祭があるのではない
It's not that there's a birthday festival because I sing...
生誕祭があるから歌うのよ
I sing because there is a birthday festival!
星の降る場所で
In the place where the stars fall
あなたが笑っていることを
That you are smiling...
いつも願ってた
I've always prayed for it
今遠くても
Even if we're far apart now
また会えるよね
We'll meet again, right?
星の降る場所へ
To the place where the stars fall
想いをあなたに届けたい
I want to deliver my feelings to you
いつも側にいる
I'm always by your side
冷たさを抱きしめるから
I will embrace that coldness
今遠くても きっと会えるね
Even if we're far apart now, we'll surely meet again
いっぱい来てくれてどうもありがとう！
Thank you so much for coming in such large numbers!
それでは次はお待ちかねのビデオレターです！
And now, up next is the video letter you've all been waiting for!
どうぞ！
Here you go!
周防パトラお姉ちゃん
Suou Patra-oneechan,
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday!
わーい！パチパチパチ！
Yay! *Clap clap clap!*
VTuberのカレンです
I'm the VTuber, Karen.
パトラお姉ちゃんは何度もカレンの番組に出てくれたりして
Patra-oneechan has appeared on my show many times,
カレン、とってもとっても感謝しています
and Karen is very, very grateful to you.
最近だと、去年の12月20日の生配信かな？
Most recently, on the live stream on December 20th last year, I think?
に、ゲストとして来てくれましたー！
You came as a guest!
カレン、それまでちょっとコールドスリープでお休みしてたんで
Until then, Karen had been resting in cold sleep,
まさかまたね、パトラお姉ちゃんがカレンの番組に来て
so I never expected Patra-oneechan to come back to my show
再会できると思ってなかったので、もうっすっごくすっごく嬉しかったんです！
and that we'd be able to reunite, so I was really, really happy!
その時は『パピプペポゲーム』で盛り上がったり
At that time, we had a lot of fun playing the "Papipepo Game"
してましたけど
and such,
皆さん見てくれたかな？
but I wonder if everyone watched it?
あ、もし見てくれてない方、アーカイブ残ってます！
Ah, if you haven't watched it yet, the archive is still up!
はい！
Yes!
そんなパトラお姉ちゃんにはカレンの、あの、ソロ曲『ラブメロディ』も
Patra-oneechan also composed my solo song, "Love Melody," for me,
パトラお姉ちゃんに作っていただいて
which was made by Patra-oneechan.
カレンね、いつかパトラお姉ちゃんと一緒に
Karen hopes that someday, together with Patra-oneechan,
その曲を、何だろう、デュエットっていうのかな？一緒に歌えたらいいなぁ
we can sing that song together as a duet or something!
っていう夢を持っています
I hold that dream in my heart.
その夢が叶うように、カレンもこれから頑張りたいと思います！
So that dream comes true, Karen will also do her best from now on!
パトラお姉ちゃんもいつまでも身体には気をつけて
Patra-oneechan, please take good care of your health always
頑張ってください！
and keep up the great work!
では、これからの1年もパトラお姉ちゃんにとって
May the coming year also be
素敵な素敵な1年になりますように！
a wonderful, wonderful year for Patra-oneechan!
パトラお姉ちゃん、大好き！
Patra-oneechan, I love you!
おやすみなさい！
Good night!
パトラちゃん お誕生日おめでとう
Patra-chan, happy birthday!
漫画家・イラストレーターの飯田ぽち。と申します
I am Iida Pochi, a manga artist and illustrator.
このお仕事をしておりますと
Doing this line of work,
時々 身心ともにエネルギー切れになってね
sometimes my mind and body run out of energy,
疲れてしまうことも多いんですけれども
and I often get exhausted.
そんな時にね いつもパトラちゃんが
But at those times, Patra-chan always says things like,
「新作楽しみにしてます！」
"I'm looking forward to your new work!"
「読みました！」とか「グッズ買いました！」とか伝えてくださるので
"I read it!" or "I bought your merch!"
いつも私 心の栄養をもらっております
so I always receive emotional nourishment from you.
パトラちゃんのおかげで いつも頑張れております
Thanks to Patra-chan, I am always able to push forward.
いつもありがとう
Thank you as always!
そんなパトラちゃんの優しさに甘えてしまっていて
Since I've been taking advantage of Patra-chan's kindness
わたくし日頃お世話になりっぱなしですので
and relying on you all the time,
そろそろね わたくしからも
I should soon
何か恩返しをさせてくださいね
do something to repay the favor to you.
いつでもね 何かあったら気軽に声かけてください
Whenever anything comes up, please feel free to reach out to me.
というわけで パトラちゃんのますますのご活躍と
So, wishing for Patra-chan's continued success
そして今年がね 素敵な一年になること
and that this year will be a wonderful year,
心から願っております
I pray from the bottom of my heart.
改めて本日はお誕生日おめでとうございます
Once again, happy birthday today!
飯田ぽち。でした
This was Iida Pochi.
おめでとう
Congratulations!
パトラちゃ〜ん！
Patra-chan~!
ハッピーバースデー！
Happy birthday!
お誕生日おめでとう〜！
Happy birthday~!
えー、にじさんじ所属の...
Um, belonging to Nijisanji...
はーい 夜見エレナでーす
Hi, I'm Yurumi Elena!
パトちゃんとはね なんだかんだつるんで まあASMR絡みが多いですけど
Pat-chan and I hang out quite a bit, though it's mostly related to ASMR...
実はおは夜見 パトちゃんとゲームも一緒にしたいなーって思ってるんだよね
Actually, I've been thinking that I'd like to play games with Pat-chan too.
なので 今度一緒にゲームで遊んでくださーい
So, please play games with me next time!
またね いつメンでご飯も行こうね
Let's also go out for a meal with the usual crew again!
もちろん 夜見と2人きりでもいいですけどね
Of course, hanging out just the two of us is fine too, though.
パトちゃんにとって素敵な1日を過ごしてね
I hope you spend a wonderful day, Pat-chan!
ほな またねー 連絡待ってまーす バイバーイ
Well then, see you later! I'll be waiting for your message! Bye-bye!
パトラ！お誕生日おめでとう！
Patra! Happy Birthday!
最高のなか また1秒1秒と この世に存在を刻んでいるね
Among these great moments, you're engraving your presence in this world second by second.
このまま永遠に刻んでいってくれよな
Keep engraving it forever like this, okay?
突然 私事なんですけれども 最近 生活リズムが終わっているんですよね
On a sudden personal note, my daily routine has been totally ruined lately.
今に始まったことじゃないんですけど
Though it's nothing new.
そこで 私はパトラのおおはよう配信から始まって ASMRおやすみ配信で終わる パトラ24が欲しいと思っているんです
So, I'm thinking I want a "Patra 24" stream that starts with Patra's good morning stream and ends with an ASMR goodnight stream!
パトラ 1日生活動画が欲しい！
I want a "Patra Day in the Life" video!
パトラで俺の生活を整えたい！
I want to fix my schedule with Patra!
どうですか？
How about it?
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
パチョー 誕生日おめでとーう！
Pacho, happy birthday!
いやー 誕生日ですか メデタイですねー
Wow, it's your birthday? How wonderful!
またね プレゼント渡しに家行くんでね ぜひぜひ入れてください
I'll visit your place to give you your present, so please do let me in!
また行くからね うち ダラダラしに行くからね グッズも持っていくからね
I'll drop by again to lounge around, and I'll bring some merch too!
おめでとう！またねー！
Congratulations! See you later!
ビデオレターありがとうございましたー！
Thank you so much for the video letters!
本当にね いろんな子たちからのビデオレター ありがたいです 家宝にします ありがとうございました！
I'm really grateful for all the video letters from everyone. I'll treasure them like family heirlooms. Thank you so much!
それではですね 次は告知になります！どうぞ！
Now then, next up we have announcements! Here you go!
皆さん こんにちはわん！
Hello everyone-wan!
周防パトラです！
It's Suou Patra!
パトダイレクトをご覧いただき ありがとうございます！
Thank you for watching PatDirect!
今日は 全部で4つの告知があります！
Today, we have four announcements in total!
それではまず こちらの告知をご覧ください！
First off, please take a look at this announcement!
ねぇ 心試してみてよ 狂う夢の...
Hey, try testing my heart, in a maddening dream...
KONAMI
この度 アミューズメント施設向けの音楽ゲーム『GITADORA』シリーズのArena Model筐体にて 楽曲収録することになりました！
My song will be included in the Arena Model cabinets of the "GITADORA" arcade game series!
なんと曲は 『メタルラブ・メソッド』！
And the song is "Metal Love Method"!
BEMANI Sound Team "あさき"さんとダブルギター！
It's a double guitar track with BEMANI Sound Team's "Asaki"!
このライブが終わったあと ゲーム内で誰でもプレイできるようになります！
After this live stream ends, anyone will be able to play it in the game!
ゲーム内の「GALAXY WAVE DELTA」カテゴリーから選曲してみてね！
Try selecting it from the "GALAXY WAVE DELTA" category in the game!
初めてGITADORAをプレイするよという人は ルーキーモードでぜひプレイしてみてください！
If it's your first time playing GITADORA, please try playing it in Rookie Mode!
また 19時からKONAMI公式YouTubeチャンネルから この楽曲のフルバージョンもアップロード予定！
Also, starting at 19:00, the full version of this song will be uploaded to KONAMI's official YouTube channel!
皆さん ぜひGITADORAで遊んでみてね！
Everyone, please be sure to give it a try on GITADORA!
やったー！ついに発表！
Hooray! Finally, the announcement!
周防パトラフィギュア第2弾が登場いたします！
The second Suou Patra scale figure is coming!
今回のテーマは ASMR配信の世界観を詰め込んだ 周防パトラ監修の完全オリジナルポーズ！
This time's theme features an all-original pose supervised by Suou Patra, packed with the atmosphere of ASMR streams!
髪の毛は透明パーツで毛先まで美しく！
Clear parts are used for the hair, making it look beautiful all the way to the tips!
お洋服のツヤ感 チョーカーやベルトの金具まで忠実に再現！
The glossy finish of her clothes, choker, and belt buckles are all faithfully recreated!
おへそ周りのシースルーは…はぁ ため息もの！
The see-through fabric around her navel... sigh, it's breathtaking!
お尻 胸 足裏まで 職人技で丁寧に仕上げました！
From her bottom and chest to the soles of her feet, it's meticulously crafted with master skill!
耳かきやクッション ラグマットも超可愛い！
The earpick, cushion, and rug mat are also super cute!
クッションにはパトラのサイン入りだよ！
The cushion even features Patra's signature!
そして 気分で楽しめる表情差し替えパーツ付き！
Plus, it comes with interchangeable face parts to match your mood!
ぎゅっとこだわりが詰まったフィギュア 楽しんでね！
Please enjoy this figure packed with so much attention to detail!
15日から開始です
Preorders start on the 15th!
予約締め切りは10月17日までだよ
Preorders close on October 17th!
絶対ゲットしてね
Be sure to get yours!
はぁ... パトラちゃん、お腹が空いて力が出ないよー
Phew... Patra-chan, I'm so hungry I have no energy~
そんな時はこれ！手作り風UMEE!パトラのカニカマカレー！
When that happens, try this! Homemade-style UMEE! Patra's Crab Stick Curry!
ピリッとスパイスのきいたカレーにカニカマがごろごろ！UMEE!
Spicy curry packed with big chunks of crab sticks! UMEE!
うわー！グラシャス！ギリギリOKだね！
Woah! Delicious! Barely made it!
ついに出た！周防パトラ全面監修！手作り風UMEE!パトラのカニカマカレー！
Finally here! Fully supervised by Suou Patra! Homemade-style UMEE! Patra's Crab Stick Curry!
2025年10月1日発売！
Releasing October 1, 2025!
1箱に2食入り！
2 servings per box!
パトラのオリジナルカードが全6種類1枚入りだよ！
Includes 1 of 6 all-new original Patra cards!
そしてなんと！パトラのUMEE皿＆パトラのUMAIスプーンセット発売だよ！
And what's more! Patra's UMEE Plate & UMAI Spoon Set is also on sale!
スプーンはパトラがイラストを描いたよ！
Patra drew the illustration on the spoon!
栄養満点！パトラの愛情も満点だよ！
Full of nutrition! Full of Patra's love too!
詳細をまたXなどで知らせるね！
I'll announce more details on X and elsewhere!
楽しみにしててね！
Look forward to it!
全部で3つの告知をご覧いただきありがとうございます！
Thank you for watching all three announcements!
GITADORA、カレー、それからフリューさんでは第2弾のフィギュアが出ることになりました！
GITADORA, the curry, and then FuRyu announced a 2nd figure coming out!
楽しみですね！
How exciting!
それでは、次で最後の告知です！ご覧ください！
Now, here is our final announcement! Please take a look!
「周防パトラ……？って、だれ？」
"Suou Patra...? Wait, who's that?"
記憶をなくしたパトラと君が織りなすもしもの物語
A "what-if" story woven by you and a Patra who lost her memories.
恋愛アドベンチャーゲーム「君色パトラIF」制作決定！
Romance Adventure Game "Kimi Iro Patra IF" in production!
「パトラのこと、拾ってくれますか？」
"Will you pick Patra up...?"
はい！ということで盛りだくさんの告知でしたー！
Alright! So those were a lot of announcements!
みんなびっくりしたー？
Did everyone get surprised?
後でね、Xの方にも情報を出しますのでよろしくお願いします！
I'll post details on X later, so please check it out!
そしてね、ここまでたくさん歌ったんですけど、次でラストの曲になります！
And also, I've sung a lot up until now, but next will be the last song!
おー！コメントもたくさんありがとうございます！
Ooh! Thank you so much for all the comments!
いやーね、今年もこうしてね、新3Dが出せたり、あの、素敵なステージでライブができたのは
Man, being able to reveal a new 3D model like this year and perform live on such a wonderful stage...
応援してくれてるみんなのおかげです！今日もね、ハッシュタグでたくさんつぶやいてくれてどうもありがとう！
...is all thanks to everyone supporting me! Thank you so much for tweeting a lot on the hashtag today as well!
そしてそして！本日のステージを作ってくださいました、ブライブグループの皆さん！本当にありがとうございました！
And also! To everyone at Brave Group who created today's stage, thank you so very much!
すごいんだよ！パトラがね、あの、パ...パンツっつった、あの、スカートの中ね、よく見せちゃうのでね、今日ね素敵なアングルを考えて撮ってくれました！本当にありがとうございます！
It's amazing! Because Patra often... shows under her skirt, they thought of such wonderful angles to shoot today! Thank you so much!
はい！それでは！次の曲、なんと新曲になります！
Alright! Now then! The next song is actually... a brand new song!
ぜひ聴いてください！
Please listen to it!
新曲は、『MINNA~!』
The new song is "MINNA~!"
MINNA~!
みんなは噛めば噛むほど味が出るもの知ってる？
Do you know what gets tastier the more you chew it?
人類の常識を超えて歴史を刻むもの教えてあげるね
Let me teach you what transcends human common sense and carves history!
MINNA! MINNA! MINNA! MINNA!
ゲームするよ！
Let's play games!
MINNA! MINNA! MINNA! MINNA!
声出していこう！
Let's hear your voices!
気がついたら24時間ゲームばかりしてる
Before I knew it, I've been playing games for 24 hours straight
現実？ 幻？ 夢の中？
Reality? Illusion? Inside a dream?
どういうわけかやめられない
For some reason I just can't stop
詰まり デバグを引いて最初からやり直し（爆破）
Getting stuck, running into bugs, resetting from the start (explosion!)
沼の中 画面の前とやめられない
Stuck in a rut, in front of the screen, I just can't stop
昔の昔の黒歴史
Dark history from long, long ago
絶対誰でもあるよ（あるよー！あるよー！）
Everyone definitely has one! (We do! We do!)
デバグちゃんどうしたのかななんて楽しい物語救い未来
Wondering what happened to Debug-chan, what a fun story, saving the future!
あの一生懸命には意味がある
That hard effort was meaningful!
パトラはいっぱいいます！
There are lots of Patras!
みんなみんなみんな叫べ！バグがあってもプロデュース！
Everyone, everyone, everyone shout! Producing even through bugs!
けれども
But still,
クソゲーなんて
there's no such thing as a trash game
この世にない
in this world!
クリアして笑って
I'll beat the game, laugh,
やるんだ
and show everyone!
君の隣
By your side,
きっと痛みも知ってるんだろう
you surely know the pain too, right?
ダサいのにね
Even though it looks uncool,
うらやましい
I envy it.
そんな風に
Living like that,
生きてみたいんだ
I want to try living like that.
いいな いいな いいな...
So nice, so nice, so nice...
気がついたらみんな
Before I realized it, everyone...
みんなと指かけたりしてる
everyone is linking pinkies with each other.
神ゲー レアゲー クソゲー
God games, rare games, trash games...
好奇心は止められない
Curiosity can't be stopped.
良いことも悪いことも
Both good things and bad things...
君の人生の味方になーれ
May they all become allies in your life!
みんな泣きな
Everyone, cry out!
みんな叫べ
Everyone, shout out!
ゲームオーバー
Game Over...
またリトライすればいい
Just retry again!
諦められない
I can't give up
ここらのゲーム
on these games here.
ハッピーエンドに行くんだ
I'm heading for a happy ending!
どこにも行かない
Going nowhere else,
夜空だけが
only the night sky
主役じゃないよね
isn't the main character, right?
汗をぬぐって キラキラ
Wiping sweat, sparkling!
悲しいときには泣けば
When you're sad, if you just cry,
いいんだよ
it's okay!
なんで苦しいことしてるんですか？
Why are you doing something so painful?
もうゴールしてもいいのかな？
Is it okay if I reach the goal now?
いやいや
No, no...
思いを込めたもののすべてを見届けたい
I want to see through everything put into these thoughts,
そんな行方が見たいだけ！
I just want to see how it turns out!
みんなみんな
Everyone, everyone
不安なんだよ
is anxious
世の中にね
in this world.
自分のこと
Is there anyone who...
許してくれる人がいるのかな？
...will forgive me?
挑戦できたら優勝！
If you can take on the challenge, you win!
みんな泣きな
Everyone, cry out!
みんな叫べ
Everyone, shout!
意味があって
There's a meaning to it,
ふりだしだけど
even if it's back to square one.
けれども
But still,
クソゲーなんて
there's no such thing as a trash game
この世にない
in this world!
クリアしてみせて
I'll clear it and show you,
笑ってやるんだ
and laugh!
はーい！お疲れ様でしたー！
Yay! Thank you for watching!
ね、あ、かにかまもいてくれたの？
Ah, Kanikama was here too?
どうもお疲れ様でした。
Thank you so much for your hard work!
いや今日はね、あ、
So today, ah...
みんなー！みんなー！みんなー！終わったよー！
Everyone! Everyone! Everyone! It's finished!
今日はね、あの、
Today, um...
なんと前回と同じステージと思いつつ、
Believe it or not, while it looks like the same stage as last time,
ちょっとね、変化があるんですよ。
there are actually a few changes.
ステージの紹介をしたいなーって思います。
I'd like to give a tour of the stage set!
まだまだあるよ！
There's still more!
見てみて見て見て、これ！
Look, look, look, look at this!
なんと前回よりもプレゼントが増えていまーす！
Believe it or not, there are even more presents than last time!
どどーん！
Ta-da!
ほらほらほら、何が入っているのかなっていうね、
Look, look, look! Wondering what's inside,
形になっているのと、あと、
they're placed like this, and also...
ここ！
Here!
かにかまが！
Kanikama is...
ちょっと変化してます！分かるでしょうか？
slightly changed! Can you tell?
えーサイゼリヤの間違い探し、じゃないですけどね、
Uh, it's not like the Saizeriya spot-the-difference,
微妙に変わっております！
but it's subtly changed!
なんと！
Believe it or not,
かにかまが増えています！
the Kanikamas have increased!
気づいた？気づいたかな？
Did you notice? Did you notice?
あとステージ全体はこうなっていまーす！
Also, the overall stage looks like this!
おー！豪華ー！
Woah! So glamorous!
すごいよね、キラキラ感も増しております！
Awesome, right? The sparkling effect has increased too!
みんなも応援ありがとー！
Thank you everyone for your support!
それからね、
And also...
でっかいね、
this big...
サムネイル！
thumbnail!
かわいい！
So cute!
同じ、同じポーズ、あ、違うような気がするけど、
The same... the same pose... Ah, feels a bit different, but...
あ、同じポーズ！
Ah, it is the same pose!
ねー！
Right?
すごい豪華に描いてもらいましたー！
It was drawn so glamorously for me!
それから、あ！
And then, ah!
はーい！シロパトラー！
Yay! Shiro-Patra!
はいはいはいはい、ちょうどね、
Yes, yes, yes, yes, right on time,
あんまりね、出番がなかったシロパトラちゃんでーす！
Shiro-Patra-chan, who didn't get much turn, is here!
ね、今日はね、1曲目に歌ってくれてどうもありがとうね、シロパトラ！
Hey, thank you so much for singing the first song today, Shiro-Patra!
てれるー！
I'm blushing!
みんなは白と黒、どっちのパトラが好き？
Which Patra do you all like, White or Black?
おっ！
Oh!
あーね！
Ah, I see!
シロパトラちゃんの方がちょっとね、
Shiro-Patra-chan is a bit...
柔らかいーの！ほら、はねてはねて！
softer! Look, bouncing, bouncing!
そうの！
That's right!
やっぱりね、パトラはね、あの鉄脚のね、
After all, Patra has those iron legs...
ベルトが巻いてあるからね、
with belts wrapped around them,
シロパトラちゃんのほうが柔らかいんですよ！
so Shiro-Patra-chan is softer!
ほらほら！
Look, look!
よく見てみて！2人のツーショット！
Look closely! A two-shot of us both!
みんな、どっちが
Everyone, which one do you...
好きかなー？
...prefer?
どっちも好き？
You like both?
あ、ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you so much!
じゃあ、高評価、チャンネル登録も
Well then, please like and subscribe,
ぜひよろしくお願いします！
we'd really appreciate it!
みんな、本当に今日はありがとー！
Everyone, thank you so much for today!
これからもよろしくねー！
Please continue to support us!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
生誕祭ライブ終わりました！
The birthday celebration live has ended!
つたない歌と豪華なステージで
On a gorgeous stage with my clumsy singing,
はしゃぐパトが今年もできたのは あなたのおかげです。
it's all thanks to you that Patra could have so much fun again this year.
今日もこの世界に生きててくれてありがとう！
Thank you for being alive in this world today!
パトは今皆といることが一番楽しいです。
Being with everyone right now brings Patra the most joy.
それはきっと世界で一番幸せなことです。
That is surely the happiest thing in the world.
周防パトラ 誕生3Dライブ 2025
[Suou Patra Birthday 3D Live 2025]